<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Project GLAIVE devblog]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Project GLAIVE devblog]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/glaive/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 01:08:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/glaive/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>This is the devblog for Project GLAIVE. A warning in advance: it's currently controlled by robots. Sure, the idea of an AI controlled devblog is a little concerning (who knows what it's even going to look like?) but I figure why not? If I actually manage to get this blog rolling in a reasonable fashion, and the site looks hideous, I'll go back and fix it later. Anyway, about the game. GLAIVE is an RPG (a meaningless acronym if there ever was one, but I won't get into that now) with a fantasy setting. A central theme of this project is representing folks who don't normally get to see themselves as the hero. When I first started toying with the idea of doing this game, I was a little embarrassed about that premise. In my heart of hearts I thought it was both self-indulgent and a bit pandering. Since then, I've come to realize how important representation really is. GX3 (also known as GaymerX) really opened my eyes up to how magical representation and belonging can truly be.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/glaive/0ad68835-2d50-4f17-8afc-1ba80256e722/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0ad68835-2d50-4f17-8afc-1ba80256e722</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 20:36:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/glaive/06379db3-59c0-42dd-bb0a-e90fedcc4691/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">06379db3-59c0-42dd-bb0a-e90fedcc4691</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 01:08:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p> I have a love-hate relationship with the StrangeIOC framework. Mostly in that I love the idea of it, but I hate the dependency chain of knowledge that one has to traverse to truly grok it. A bit of background, first. I've been fixated on the idea of utilizing MVC as a way of future-proofing a codebase which will inevitably be overhauled and redesigned. My initial GLAIVE combat prototype was written in spaghetti.NET, because I wanted to short-circuit my tendency to over-nuke the code. Now that I'm doing a more complete prototype, I've decided to take the opportunity to write this module in the practice I intend to utilize for the whole game. Anyway, back to Strange. Strange is chiefly designed for the Flash game dev who migrated to Unity. It's based on the same principles as the robotlegs framework for that platform. Sadly for me, I never touched Flash, so I'm approaching it purely from a Unity dev's perspective. List of other things I also had no experience with prior to encountering Strange: Dependency Injection. Reflection. Using someone else's framework for your project. Etc. Fortunately for me, a few projects at work also use Strange. This provides me with ample opportunity to look at Strange in an environment outside of the examples that ship with it. These projects utilize the most powerful aspects of the framework, that is, the ability to swap whole subsystems out at build-time. This is extremely helpful for things like analytics or platform-dependent systems. Sadly, at this early stage my project benefits not at all from that capability. Right now I'm mostly focused on how I can use Strange to enforce an MVC paradigm without resorting to odious reference-passing or making everything public/a singleton/actual contract with Satan written in blood. I have a bit of a prototype-within-a-prototype that I've been munching on, and it looks like it's finally coming together via much tribulation. Now, I'd like to stop at this point and mention that the documentation for Strange is actually very good. Some of the best I've seen, as a matter of fact. I just don't think it was written for me, necessarily. Thusfar I've been piecing together an understanding of the framework through a combination of: friends who know and use Strange themselves, docs, examples, and literally complaining to the author (whose patience and humor are boundless, I might add.) As I mentioned earlier, my earnest forays seem to developing nicely. Here's to hoping that it pays off. Will share progress on this topic as the situation progresses.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/glaive/i-have-a-love-hate-relationship-with-the-strangeioc-framewo/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">def0c60e-b961-43de-9d99-72d646412676</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 21:14:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/b464e8b9-96dd-42b5-bff5-ee4ac98fcdf7.png">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/glaive/be08c07e-89e1-4236-9372-cc39ef0997fb/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">be08c07e-89e1-4236-9372-cc39ef0997fb</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 03:59:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>